Blake Fromkin

➡ blakefromkin@gmail.com
Opensonal Site

PROFILE

I'm a full-stack software engineer with multiple years of experience in the JavaScript/TypeScript ecosystem, and I'm also proficient with Go. I leverage the creative problem-solving skills I honed in my previous role as an Associate Creative Director to tackle complex engineering challenges and communicate effectively with my teammates. Most recently, I co-created Reverb 2 , an event-driven workflow engine that orchestrates the logic and infrastructure developers need to build complex background sequences.

SKILLS

Back-End

Node.js, Express, Golang, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST APIs, Handlebars, Jest

Cloud

AWS, DigitalOcean, Heroku, Fly.io

Front-End

JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, React, jQuery, HTML/CSS

Other

Git/GitHub, GH Actions, Docker, WebSockets, Microservices, Queues, SQL, HTTP, OOP, Nginx, Postman, Bash

EXPERIENCE

Co-Creator & Software Engineer, Reverb

Reverb is an open-source, event-driven workflow engine that reliably orchestrates complex, multi-step background sequences.

- Built a robust orchestration pipeline that can accommodate a variety of workflow triggers (events, cron, third-party webhooks) and task types (jobs, delays, conditional branching, fan-out)
- Designed a microservices architecture with nodes for ingestion, queuing, and execution (AWS Lambda, EC2, ECS/Fargate, RDS, IAM)
- Reduced cloud deployment from 152 steps to 1 command, and automated CI/CD for containerizing and redeploying workflows (AWS CDK, GitHub Actions, Docker)
- Constructed durable PostgreSQL-backed job queues to withstand crashes and reliably execute long-running sequences (Graphile Worker, Node.js, TypeScript)
- Implemented memoization with object caches to maintain workflow state across repeated TypeScript function invocations
- Designed a RESTful API with UI and CLI tools for retrieving logs, tracing events, and monitoring workflow progress (API Gateway, Lambda, MongoDB, React)
- Created a TypeScript SDK and NPM create script for developers to easily install template code, define workflows as step functions, and expose them to remote procedure calls
- Collaborated with an international team of four engineers via daily standups & solo/pair/mob programming (Git, GitHub, Trello)
- Served as lead author for a comprehensive <u>technical case study</u>

Software Engineer, *Open-Source Projects*

2022 - 2024

2024

A selection of open-source projects developed during my career transition:

- HTTP Hoarder Real-time tool for collecting and debugging webhook requests (DigitalOcean Droplet, Nginx, WebSockets, MongoDB, Express, React)
- WatchIt Database-backed app to track, rate, and queue movie viewings (Express, PostgreSQL, Vanilla JS, Handlebars)
- Draft Lottery Server-side rendered (SSR) app I built for my fantasy football league's weighted draft lottery. (Express, Vanilla JS, Pug)

Associate Creative Director & Copywriter, Publicis

2019 - 2023

- Led and collaborated with cross-functional teams to generate award-winning integrated campaigns on tight deadlines
- Consistently delivered against clients' diverse business goals, incorporated feedback, and ran client-facing presentations

EDUCATION

Launch School 2022 – 2024

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum. Read more at launchschool.com/employers 🗵

Northwestern University

2012 - 2016

- Summa Cum Laude
- Television/Film & Integrated Marketing Communications